Guide to the Gertrude Stein and Alice B. Toklas Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Gertrude Stein Correspondence, 1893-1946; Series II; 16.25; (40 boxes)
  - GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE
    - Faÿ, Bernard, 1926-46, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 2095-2101)
      Includes: drafts of writings by BF: "Préface" to the Autobiography of ABT, "Portrait de Miss Gertrude Stein," and "Essais sur la Poesie"
      Also includes: drafts of statements by GS on behalf of BF (to Maitre Chresteil)
    - Federleicht, Hortense; Federleicht, Louis, 1906-30 (Box 106, Folder 2102)
    - Fellowes, Daisy, [1934-46], n.d. (Box 106, Folder 2103)
    - Fénéon, Félix
      See: Bernheim Jeune et Cie.
    - Ferdoquier, Germaine de, 1938, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 2104)
    - Ferren, John, 1936 (Box 106, Folder 2105)
    - Fifield, Arthur C., 1912 Apr 19 (Box 106, Folder 2106)
    - Fifth Avenue Bank of New York, 1935 (Box 106, Folder 2107)
    - Fish, Marjorie, 1934 May 9 (Box 106, Folder 2108)
    - Fitts, Dudley, 1934-36 (Box 106, Folder 2109)
      Includes: letters from Fitts to Marvin Chancey Ross
    - Fitzgerald, F. Scott (Francis Scott), 1925-34 (Box 106, Folder 2109a)
    - Fitzgerald, Zelda, 1944 [1945?] Apr 15 (Box 106, Folder 2110)
    - Flanner, Janet, 1933, 1939, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 2111)
    - Flato, Charles, 1933 May 11 (Box 106, Folder 2112)
    - Flechtheim, Alfred, 1929, 1930, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 2113)
    - Fletcher, Constance, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 2114)
    - Floury, H., 1938 Jun 27 (Box 107, Folder 2115)
    - Foley, Martha
      See: Whit Burnett
    - Fontaine, 1941, 1945 (Box 107, Folder 2116)
      See also: Jean Denoël
    - Fonteyn, Margot, 1937 Apr 27 (Box 107, Folder 2117)
    - Foote, Mary, 1912 (Box 107, Folder 2118)
    - Ford, Charles Henri, 1929-34, n.d. (Box 107, Folder 2119)
      Includes: draft of "A little boy had a sty in his eye..." by GS
    - Ford, Ford Madox, 1924-28, n.d. (Box 107, Folder 2120)
    - Ford, Esther Ford, Julia
      GS: draft of letter to The Nation and to "Paul"
      See: Series I., Writings, Carnets - [1924], Box 92, folder 1713 for GS: draft of letter to FMF
      Includes: letter from Stella Bowen to GS
    - Fort, Paul, 1906-07 (Box 107, Folder 2121)
    - The Four Seas Company, 1921-30 (Box 107, Folder 2122-2123)
      GS: draft of response and draft of letter
      Includes: letter from The Four Seas Co. to Kate Buss (1921), and letters from Herbert Ehrmann to GS
    - Fourquier, Raymond, 1912 (Box 107, Folder 2124)
    - Foyle, Christina, 1940 May 16 (Box 107, Folder 2125)
    - Franceschini, 1938 Jun 13 (Box 107, Folder 2126)
    - Francis, Esther, n.d. (Box 107, Folder 2127)
    - Frank, Ellen, 1934, n.d. (Box 107, Folder 2128)
    - Frank, Waldo, 1913 Mar 12 (Box 107, Folder 2129)
    - Frere, Rosamond, 1936 Jan (Box 107, Folder 2130)
    - Fridberg, Maurice, 1946 (Box 107, Folder 2131)
    - Friedman, Leo Victor, 1895-1907 (Box 107, Folder 2132)
      See also: Adele Oppenheimer
    - Friend, Krebs
    - Fritz, Bernardine Szold
      See: Bernardine Szold
    - Fry, Charles
      See: B. T. Batsford, Ltd.
    - Fry, Roger, 1913, 1919 (Box 107, Folder 2133)
    - Furman, Lee
      See: Macauley Company
    - "G" general, 1911-46, n.d. (Box 107, Folder 2134)
    - Galantière, Lewis; Galantière, Dorothy, 1926, n.d. (Box 107, Folder 2135)
    - Galerie Pierre, n.d. (Box 107, Folder 2136)
    - Gallatin, A. E., 1926 Jun 15 (Box 107, Folder 2137)
    - Gandolac, Mr. (Box 107, Folder 2138)
    - Gannett, Lewis, 1934, [1935] (Box 107, Folder 2139)
    - Gans, Howard; Gans, Bird (Sternberger); Gans, Marion S., 1896-1945 (Box 107, Folder 2140-2142)
      Includes: letters from BG and HG to Michael and Sally Stein, letter from HG to Sarah Stein (transcribed by GS), 1906 Dec 3
    - Garden, Mary, [1935?] Apr (Box 107, Folder 2143)
      See: Series I., Writings, Carnets - [1930], Box 93, folder 1730 for GS: draft of letter
    - Gassette, Grace; Gassette, Amelia, 1908-15 (Box 107, Folder 2144)
    - Gaudet, E.; Gaudet, M., 1929-41 (Box 107, Folder 2145)
    - Genevrey, Frédéric; Genevrey, M. Therése, 1925-34, n.d. (Box 107, Folder 2146)
    - Genin, Paul, 1942-45, n.d. (Box 107, Folder 2147)
      Includes: letter from "Elena" to GS, letter from "Nena" to GS, letters from "Joan" to GS, and letters from the Comité France-Amérique
    - George, Waldemar, 1923-26, n.d. (Box 107, Folder 2148)
    - Germain, André (Box 107, Folder 2149)
    - Gerould, Katharine Fullerton, 1934 (Box 107, Folder 2150)
    - Gerstle, Hilda Hecht, 1923 (Box 107, Folder 2151)
    - Gervasi, Frank, 1945 Mar 13 (Box 108, Folder 2152)
    - [Geuge?], Jack E., 1921-22 (Box 108, Folder 2153)
      See also: Sadie Gibb
    - Gibb, Harriet, 1912-13 (Box 108, Folder 2154)
    - Gibb, Henry Phelan, 1911-33, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 2155-2156)
      (includes clippings)
    - Gibb, Marjory, 1914-31 (Box 108, Folder 2157)
    - Gibb, Sadie
      See also: Jack E. [Geuge?]
    - Gillet, Louis, 1933 Sep 6 (Box 108, Folder 2158)
    - Gillette, William, 1935 May 28 (Box 108, Folder 2159)
    - Giraud, André; Giraud, Marthe, 1930-43, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 2160)
    - Gittes, Archie, 1933-41, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 2161)
    - Giulio Einaudi Editore, 1937-40 (Box 108, Folder 2162)
      Includes: letters from Cesare Pavese, and letters from Vito Pandolfi
      Also includes: preface (holograph) to Italian translation of Three Lives (Tre Esistenze) in hand of Pavese
    - Glasgow, Ellen, 1935 (Box 108, Folder 2163)
    - Glass, Douglas, 1930-33 (Box 108, Folder 2164)
    - Glick, Annie, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 2165)
      [several fragments of letters]
    - Godet, Raymond, 1946 Mar 29 (Box 108, Folder 2166)
    - Godet, Silvia; Godet, Robert; Godet, Mark; Godet, Moki, 1941-45, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 2167)
    - Gogarty, Oliver St. John, 1914 Jan 24 (Box 108, Folder 2168)
    - Gonzales, Georges, 1928-40 (Box 108, Folder 2169)
      Includes: letters also signed by Lucie [Kahnweiler]
    - Goodspeed, Bobsy
      See: Elizabeth Fuller ("Bobsy") Chapman
    - Gorer, Geoffrey, 1926-30 (Box 108, Folder 2170)
    - Goulston and Storrs Wings
      See: William A. Bradley
    - Gourion, Suzanne, 1940-41 (Box 108, Folder 2171)
    - Grafton Press, 1908-11 (Box 108, Folder 2172)
    - Graham, Joan, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 2173)
    - Grant, Duncan, 1914 Feb (Box 108, Folder 2174)
    - Grant, John, 1912 Mar 4 (Box 108, Folder 2175)
    - Grant-Watson, E. L., 1912, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 2176)
    - Grautoff, Otto, 1912 Apr 6 (Box 108, Folder 2177)
    - Graves, Robert, [1929?]-46 (Box 108, Folder 2178)
    - Gray, Eileen, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 2179)
    - Green, Andrew, 1903-22 (Box 108, Folder 2180)
    - Green, Julien, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 2181)
    - Gregory, Alyse, 1928 Aug 11 (Box 108, Folder 2182)
    - Greif, Amy Federlicht, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 2183)
    - Griffin, Edith, 1919-20, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 2184)
    - Griggs, Arthur K., n.d. (Box 108, Folder 2185)
    - Griggs, Emily, 1919-20 (Box 108, Folder 2186)
    - Gris, George
      See: Georges Gonzales
    - Gris, Josette, 1925-45, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 2187)
    - Gris, Juan, 1914-27 (Box 108, Folder 2188)
    - Gros, Robert R., 1937-38 (Box 109, Folder 2189)
    - Grosser, Maurice, n.d. (Box 109, Folder 2190)
    - Grubb, G. H.
      See: Chapman and Hall
    - Guevara, Alvaro, 1927-43, n.d. (Box 109, Folder 2191)
    - Guevara, Meraud, 1929-38, n.d. (Box 109, Folder 2192)
    - Guhlenschub, L., 1918, n.d. (Box 109, Folder 2193)
    - Guggenheimer, Julia; Guggenheimer, Carrie; Guggenheimer, Hetty, 1915-34, n.d. (Box 109, Folder 2194)
    - Guitry, Sacha, n.d. (Box 109, Folder 2195)
    - Gunet, Edwige; Gunet, Ph., 1942-45 (Box 109, Folder 2196)
    - "H" general, 1898-1946, n.d. (Box 109, Folder 2197)
    - Haas, Robert Bartlett, 1935-46 (Box 109, Folder 2198-2200)
    - Habasque, Alain, 1945, n.d. (Box 109, Folder 2201)
    - Habasque, Guy, n.d. (Box 109, Folder 2202)
    - [Haesehr?], A., 1906-10 (Box 109, Folder 2203)
    - Hale, Maryse Rutledge, n.d. (Box 109, Folder 2204)
    - Halicka, Alice
      See: Louis Marcoussis
    - Hall, Radclyffe, n.d. (Box 109, Folder 2205)
    - Hamilton, John, 1937-39 (Box 109, Folder 2206)
    - Hamilton, Nancy
      See: Katharine Cornell
    - Hannibal, George E., 1918 (Box 109, Folder 2207)
    - Hansen, Agnes; Hansen, Lilyana, 1924-34 (Box 109, Folder 2208)
    - Hapgood, Hutchins; Hapgood, Neith Boyce; Hapgood, Norman, [1905?]-1910 (Box 109, Folder 2209)
    - Harcourt, Alfred
      See: Harcourt, Brace, and Co.
    - Harcourt, Brace, and Co., 1933-1939 (Box 109, Folder 2210)
      GS: notes and draft of letter
      Includes: letters addressed to Etta Cone
    - Harcourt, Ellen
    - Harden, Elmer; Harden, Emily; Harden, Ida, 1920-39, n.d. (Box 109, Folder 2211)
    - Hardy, Jane, 1936 Apr 3 (Box 109, Folder 2212)
    - Hardy, [Thomas], n.d. (Box 109, Folder 2213)
      [contains only: draft of letter from GS for appeal for Mildred Aldrich]
    - Hardy, Walter Badenoch; Hardy, Katharine E., 1916-28, n.d. (Box 109, Folder 2214)
      Includes holograph manuscript on Arabian doorways
    - Harmsworth, Desmond, 1932-33 (Box 109, Folder 2215)
    - Harper, Allanah, 1929-31, n.d. (Box 109, Folder 2216)
    - Harper and Brothers, 1919-37, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 2217)
    - Harper's Bazaar, 1931-39 (Box 110, Folder 2218)
    - Harris, Sibyl, 1920-41, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 2219)
    - Harrison, Fanneal, 1918 (Box 110, Folder 2220)
    - Harrison, Gilbert, 1933-38 (Box 110, Folder 2221)
    - [Harrison, Lou?], n.d. (Box 110, Folder 2222)
    - Hartley, Marsden, 1912-34 (Box 110, Folder 2223-2224)
    - Hasselriis, Mark, 1945 (Box 110, Folder 2225)
    - Harvey, Dorothy Dudley, 1928-34 (Box 110, Folder 2226)
    - Hauke, César de, 1940-44 (Box 110, Folder 2227)
    - Haweis, Stephen, 1911-[37?] (Box 110, Folder 2228)
    - Haygood, Vardi; Haygood, William, 1945 (Box 110, Folder 2229)
    - Haynes-Heissig, Mabel, 1907-28, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 2230)
    - Heap, Jane, 1923-28, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 2231)
    - Heap, Tom Heap, Fritz
      Includes: letter from Stanley Moss to JH
      See also: Boni and Liveright
    - Heathcote, Dudley, 1931 (Box 110, Folder 2232)
    - Hecht, Alice F., 1926, 1929 (Box 110, Folder 2233)
    - Heck, A., 1919, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 2234)
    - Heinemann [firm], 1912-34 (Box 110, Folder 2235)
      Includes: letter from Heinemann to Henry Phelan Gibbs
    - Hierath, Alexander; Hierath, Mary, 1899-1911 (Box 110, Folder 2236)
      Includes photographic postcard of Mary Heirath
    - Helburn, Theresa, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 2237)
    - Helpmann, Robert, 1937 (Box 110, Folder 2238)
      [one letter from "Sailor"]
    - Hemingway, Ernest, 1922-25 (Box 110, Folder 2239-2240)
      Includes photographic postcards of Ernest Hemingway in bullfight ring
    - Hemingway, Hadley
      See: Hadley Mowrer
    - Hemingway, Pauline, 1928, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 2241)
    - Herbert Jenkins, Ltd., 1913 (Box 110, Folder 2242)
    - Herring, Robert, 1928, 1936 (Box 110, Folder 2243)
    - Heyligers, Jan, 1932-34 (Box 110, Folder 2244)
    - Heyward, DuBose, [1935] Apr 6 (Box 110, Folder 2245)
    - Hibbit, George W., 1934-45 (Box 110, Folder 2246)
    - [EMPTY FOLDER] (Box 110, Folder 2247)
    - Higham, David
      See: Pearn, Pollinger, and Higham, Ltd.
    - Hill, Willard, 1943 (Box 110, Folder 2248)
      GS: draft of Castles They Live In
    - Hitchcock, Henry Russell, 1930-31 (Box 110, Folder 2249)
    - Hockaday, Ela, 1937-[39?], n.d. (Box 110, Folder 2250)
    - Hofmann, Gérard, 1942-43 (Box 111, Folder 2251)
    - Holly, Flora M., 1906-07 (Box 111, Folder 2252)
    - Holt, Nora, 1926-31 (Box 111, Folder 2253)
    - Hone, Joseph; Hone, Vera, 1921-28 (Box 111, Folder 2254)
    - Hopwood, Avery, 1923-28 (Box 111, Folder 2255)
    - Horwood, Henry A., 1928-45 (Box 111, Folder 2256)
      GS: draft of letter [to Bravig Imbs?]
      See: Series I., Writings, Carnets - [1929-30], Box 93, folder 1729 for GS: draft of letter
    - Hotel Algonquin
    - Hotel du Luxembourg, 1918 (Box 111, Folder 2257)
    - Houghton, Mary, 1925, n.d. (Box 111, Folder 2258)
    - The Hound and Horn, Inc.
      See: Lincoln Kirstein
    - The Hours Press, n.d. (Box 111, Folder 2259)
    - Hristodoulovitch, Juliette, 1942-46, n.d. (Box 111, Folder 2260)
    - Hubbell, Lindley Williams, 1928-41 (Box 111, Folder 2261)
      Includes: letter from LWH to Eugene Jolas with "A Letter to Gertrude Stein," typescript, and a review of The Plain Edition of Gertrude Stein, typescript
      GS: notes for Page IX
    - Huebsch, B. W., 1912-25 (Box 111, Folder 2262)
      Includes: letter from BWH to Sherwood Anderson, and letters from BWH to Jane Heap
    - Hueffer, Muriel (Harris), 1916, n.d. (Box 111, Folder 2263)
    - Hugnet, Georges, 1927-1930, n.d. (Box 111, Folder 2264-2266)
    - Hugnet, Marthe
      See: Series I., Writings, Answer to: Why I do not live in America - Manuscript notebooks, Box 3, folder 60 for GS: draft of letter
      Includes: "Les Iles Fortunée," holograph (1927), and "Le Berceau de Gertrude Stein" (1928)
    - Hugnet, Georges (father of Georges), 1929, 1931 (Box 111, Folder 2267)
    - Hull, Elizabeth Shaffer, n.d. (Box 111, Folder 2268)
    - Humbert, Marcelle
      See: Eva Gouël Picasso
    - Hunt, Cecil, n.d. (Box 111, Folder 2269)
      GS: draft fragment
    - Hunt, Sidney, 1926-27 (Box 111, Folder 2270)
    - Hunt, Violet (Hueffer), 1913 Apr 3 (Box 111, Folder 2271)
    - Hurd, Clement, 1939-40, n.d. (Box 111, Folder 2272)
    - Hutchins, Robert M., 1935 Jan 8 (Box 111, Folder 2273)
    - "I" general, 1927-46, n.d. (Box 111, Folder 2274)
    - Ignatius, Herbert, 1945 Sep 7 (Box 111, Folder 2275)
    - Imbs, Bravig, 1926-46, n.d. (Box 111, Folder 2276-2277)
      GS: drafts of responses and draft of the contract for Making of Americans
      See: Series I., Writings, Lucy Church amiably - carnets for GS: draft of letter
      Includes: "The Chateau and Monsieur Joubeaux" by BI, typescript carbon [1940?]
    - Imes, Nella Larsen, 1929-1931, n.d. (Box 111, Folder 2278)
    - Imprimerie "Union", 1930 Jun 19 (Box 111, Folder 2279)
    - Incorporated Society of Authors, Playwrights, and Composers, 1927 Sep 27 (Box 111, Folder 2280)
    - Ingersoll, R. Sturgis, 1934 Nov (Box 111, Folder 2281)
    - Internationale Literarische Agentur, 1929-30 (Box 111, Folder 2282)
    - "J" general, 1907-46, n.d. (Box 112, Folder 2283)
    - Jaccaci, August F., 1921-1925 (Box 112, Folder 2284)
    - Jackson, Holbrook, 1913-14, n.d. (Box 112, Folder 2285)
    - Jackson, Laura (Riding), 1927-30 (Box 112, Folder 2286-2287)
      GS: notes, drafts of responses
      See: Series I., Writings, Carnets - [1928], Box 92, folder 1725 for GS: draft of letter
      See also: Robert Graves
    - Jacob, Max, 1929-39, n.d. (Box 112, Folder 2288)
    - Jacobs, Polly; Jacobs, Frank, 1910-14, n.d. (Box 112, Folder 2289)
    - Jacott, Frank, 1908-29, n.d. (Box 112, Folder 2290)
      Includes: postcard from ["Affie"?]
    - Jacott, Nellie, 1908-29, n.d. (Box 112, Folder 2291)
    - Jaffa, Adele, n.d. (Box 112, Folder 2292)
    - James, Edward, 1936 Apr 23 (Box 112, Folder 2293)
    - James, William, 1896-1910 (Box 112, Folder 2294)
    - Jewett, William Dunbar, 1917-23, n.d. (Box 112, Folder 2295)
    - John, George, n.d. (Box 112, Folder 2296)
    - John Lane Publishers
      See: John Lane
    - Johns, Richard
      See: Pagany
    - Johnson, Alvin, 1934 Nov 7 (Box 112, Folder 2297)
    - Johnson, Lamont; Johnson, Toni; Johnson, Margot, 1945-46 (Box 112, Folder 2298)
      See: Ann Watkins, Inc.
    - Johnston, Jean M. Browne; Johnston, Dorothy; Johnston, William Dawson, 1924-25, n.d. (Box 112, Folder 2299)
      See: American Library in Paris
    - Jolas, Eugene, 1927-31 (Box 112, Folder 2300)
    - Jolas, Maria
      Includes: letter from Walter Leigh to Transition
    - Jonathan Cape, Ltd., 1924-25 (Box 112, Folder 2301)
    - Jones, Llewellyn, 1927 Jul 22 (Box 112, Folder 2302)
    - Jones, Richard, 1934 (Box 112, Folder 2303)
    - [Jones, Richard?], 1934 Apr (Box 112, Folder 2304)
    - Jouhandeau, Marcél, 1936, n.d. (Box 112, Folder 2305)
    - [Juasitch?], O., n.d. (Box 112, Folder 2306)
      ABT: draft of response
    - "K" general, 1908-45, n.d. (Box 112, Folder 2307)
    - Kahn, Ivan, 1935 Aug 28 (Box 112, Folder 2308)
    - Kahn, Ivan, 1935-36 (Box 112, Folder 2309)
    - Kahnweiler, Daniel-Henry, 1912-41 (Box 112, Folder 2310-2311)
      Includes: notes on The Autobiography of ABT by DHK and clipping
    - Kahnweiler, Lucie, [1927?]-40, n.d. (Box 112, Folder 2312)
    - [Karn?], Alphonse, n.d. (Box 112, Folder 2313)
    - Kasparek-Grodecki, John, 1938 (Box 113, Folder 2314)
    - Kaufman, Lilian, 1938 (Box 113, Folder 2315)
    - Kaufman, Stella; Kaufman, Adolf, 1910-11, n.d. (Box 113, Folder 2316)
    - Kegan Paul, Trench, Trubner and Co., Ltd., 1928 (Box 113, Folder 2317)
    - Kellogg, Spencer, 1926, n.d. (Box 113, Folder 2318)
    - Kelly, Albert, 1944-45 (Box 113, Folder 2319)
    - Kelsey, Laura F. B., 1908 (Box 113, Folder 2320)
    - Kemper, Gertrude Raffel, n.d. (Box 113, Folder 2321)
    - Kennedy, John F. (Jack), n.d. (Box 113, Folder 2322)
    - Kennon, Robert F., 1945-46 (Box 113, Folder 2323)
      GS: sketches
    - Keogh, Andrew
    - Kessinger, Boyd F., 1945, n.d. (Box 113, Folder 2324)
    - Keyser, Beatrice; Keyser, Ernest, 1906-34 (Box 113, Folder 2325)
    - Keyser, Ephraim, 1906-17 (Box 113, Folder 2326)
      Includes: letter to Mike [Stein?] (1913)
    - Keyser, Rachel, 1911-[16?] (Box 113, Folder 2327)
    - Keyser, Solomon; Keyser, Helen, 1911-12 (Box 113, Folder 2328)
      Includes: letter from "Dorothy" to SK and HK, letter from Celia to SK and HK, and draft of letter from Helen Veyser to Mr. and Mme. Schöninger
    - King, Georgiana Goddard, 1906-34 (Box 113, Folder 2329)
    - King, Stanley; King, Margaret Pinckney, 1934, 1936 (Box 113, Folder 2330)
    - Kirstein, Lincoln, 1932-34 (Box 113, Folder 2331)
    - Klein, John M., 1939 Oct 16 (Box 113, Folder 2332)
    - Klopfer, Donald S.
      See: Bennett Cerf
    - Knoblauch, Edward, n.d. (Box 113, Folder 2333)
    - Knoblauch, May (Mary) Bookstaver, 1910, n.d. (Box 113, Folder 2334)
      See also: Grafton Press
    - Knollenberg, Bernhard
    - Knopf, Alfred; Knopf, Blanche; Knopf, Alfred, Jr., 1919-[34] (Box 113, Folder 2335)
    - Kohn, Estelle Rumbold; Kohn, Robert, 1906-14, n.d. (Box 113, Folder 2336)
    - Korzybska, Mira Edgerly; Korzybski, Alfred, 1912-34 (Box 113, Folder 2337)
      Includes: letter from MEK to "Miss Halsey"
      GS: telegrams and typescript copies of letters to MEK
    - Kreymborg, Alfred, 1921-30, n.d. (Box 113, Folder 2338)
    - Krakauer, Alice, 1908, n.d. (Box 113, Folder 2339)
    - Krishna, Roop, 1939 (Box 113, Folder 2340)
      GS: postcard (cancelled) to RK
    - Kuhn, Walt, 1912 Nov 7 (Box 113, Folder 2341)
    - Kuntz, Charles, Mrs., 1939 Apr [18?] (Box 113, Folder 2342)
    - "L" general, 1907-46, n.d. (Box 113, Folder 2343)
    - Lachenal, François, 1943 Dec 13 (Box 113, Folder 2344)
    - Lachman, Arthur, 1896-[98?] (Box 113, Folder 2345)
    - La Farge, Bancel, 1911-12 (Box 113, Folder 2346)
    - Lager, Paulette M. A., 1945, n.d. (Box 113, Folder 2347)
    - La Motte, Ellen, 1913-36, n.d. (Box 113, Folder 2348)
    - Lane, John; Lane, Annie, 1913-37, n.d. (Box 113, Folder 2349)
      Includes: letter from JL to Miss [Mira] Edgerly [Korzybska]
    - Langlois, L. Jean-Paul, 1928-29, n.d. (Box 113, Folder 2350)
    - Larbaud, Valery, 1920 Nov 3 (Box 113, Folder 2351)
    - Larsson, R. Ellsworth, n.d. (Box 113, Folder 2352)
    - Larus
      See: John Sherry Mangan
    - Lascaux, Elie, 1928-46 (Box 114, Folder 2353)
    - [Lasteyrie], Louis de, n.d. (Box 114, Folder 2354)
    - Lathrop, Isabel, 1921-45 (Box 114, Folder 2355)
    - Laughlin, James, 1934-[45?] (Box 114, Folder 2356)
    - Laughlin, Mr. [James?], n.d. (Box 114, Folder 2357)
    - Laurencin, Marie, 1907-45, n.d. (Box 114, Folder 2358)
    - Lavocat, Hélène, 1910-35, n.d. (Box 114, Folder 2359)
    - Lebender, Lena, 1907, 1913, n.d. (Box 114, Folder 2360)
    - Lee, Arthur, 1913, n.d. (Box 114, Folder 2361)
    - Lee, John C. H., 1945 Apr 12 (Box 114, Folder 2362)
    - Lee, Ulysses G., Jr., 1933, 1934 (Box 114, Folder 2363)
      GS: draft of letter [includes draft of letter to Bernard]
    - Leglaye, Abel, 1918-20, n.d. (Box 114, Folder 2364-2365)
    - Leigh, W. Colston, 1934, 1940 (Box 114, Folder 2366)
      Includes: letters from WCL to William Bradley and John G. McCullough
    - Leiris, Michel; Leiris, Madame, 1931, n.d. (Box 114, Folder 2367)
    - Leyris, Pierre; Leyris, Elizabeth, 1939, 1941, n.d. (Box 114, Folder 2368)
    - Levy, Harriet, 1908-35, n.d. (Box 114, Folder 2369-2370)
    - Levy, Julius; Levy, Etta, n.d. (Box 114, Folder 2371)
    - Lewis, Lloyd, 1935-37 (Box 114, Folder 2372)
    - Librarie Stock
    - Lifar, 1932 Apr 18 (Box 114, Folder 2373)
    - Life, 1917, 1919 (Box 114, Folder 2374)
    - Life and Letters To-Day
      See: Robert Herring
    - [EMPTY FOLDER] (Box 114, Folder 2375)
    - Lin, Adet; Lin, Tsuifeng, 1938-39 (Box 114, Folder 2376)
    - Lindo-Webb, James; Lindo-Webb, Lettie, 1916, 1921, n.d. (Box 114, Folder 2377)
    - Link, Joseph, Jr., 1945-46 (Box 114, Folder 2378)
    - Lipchitz, Jacques, 1921-33, n.d. (Box 114, Folder 2379)
    - Lippmann, Walter, 1915 Apr 13 (Box 114, Folder 2380)
    - Littlefield, Lester, 1934, 1941 (Box 114, Folder 2381)
      Includes: letter from LL to Bennett Cerf
    - Livengood, Ed, 1939, n.d. (Box 114, Folder 2382)
    - Lloyd, M. Constance, n.d. (Box 114, Folder 2383)
    - Locher, Beatrice; Locher, Robert, 1923-31, n.d. (Box 114, Folder 2384)
    - Loeb, Harold, [1922?-23?] (Box 114, Folder 2385)
      GS: draft of inscription to Georgiana Goddard King
    - Loeser, Charles, 1909, n.d. (Box 114, Folder 2386)
    - The London Mercury, 1925 (Box 114, Folder 2387)
    - Long, John F., 1918, n.d. (Box 114, Folder 2388)
    - Lord, James, 1945, n.d. (Box 114, Folder 2389)
    - Lounsbery, Grace Constant, 1921-22, n.d. (Box 114, Folder 2390)
    - Love, Allen
    - Lovejay, Charles R., 1918-19 (Box 115, Folder 2391)
    - Lovett, Robert, 1922-23 (Box 115, Folder 2392)
      Includes: letter from RL to Jo Davidson
    - Lowenfels, Walter, [1926], 1932 (Box 115, Folder 2393)
    - Loy, Mina, 1911, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 2394)
    - Luce, Clare Booth, 1939-40 (Box 115, Folder 2395)
    - Lucha, Margaret, [1936]-37 (Box 115, Folder 2396)
    - Luhan, Mabel Dodge, 1911-34, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 2397-2403)
      Includes: "Exhortation" by MDL, letters from Paul Ayrault to MDL (1912), letters from Emily [Chadbourne?] to MDL (n.d.), and from Mabel to MDL (n.d.)
    - Lutz, Mark, [1934]-45 (Box 115, Folder 2404)
    - Lye, Len, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 2405)
    - Lynes, George Platt, [1925]-[44?] (Box 115, Folder 2406)
      GS: notes and draft of letter to John Lee Andrew
      Includes: Cable from GPL to Allen Tanner (1926), letter from GPL to M. C. Ross (1934), and letter to GPL from Michel Licht (1934).
    - Lyon, George, 1933-34 (Box 115, Folder 2407)
    - Lyon, John H. H., 1934, 1941 (Box 115, Folder 2408)
    - Lyons, Leonard, 1948 Jun 29 (Box 115, Folder 2409)
    - "M" general, 1908-46, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 2410-2411)
    - McAlmon, Robert, 1923-26 (Box 115, Folder 2412)
      GS: notes, drafts of responses, and proof of title page for The Making of Americans
    - McBride, Henry, 1913-37 (Box 115, Folder 2413)
      GS: Christmas card from GS to HM
    - McCan, Isqua, 1938-39 (Box 115, Folder 2414)
    - McCausland, Elizabeth, 1934 (Box 115, Folder 2415)
    - McClintic, Guthrie, [1938?] Apr 30 (Box 115, Folder 2416)
    - McClure's Magazine, 1911 (Box 115, Folder 2417)
    - McCole, Camille, 1933 Jun 29 (Box 115, Folder 2418)
    - McCormick, Harold, 1935, 1937 (Box 115, Folder 2419)
    - McCullough, John G.